<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Wyatt Walsh</title><link>https://wwalsh.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Wyatt Walsh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wwalsh.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Artificial Intelligence</title><link>https://wwalsh.io/interests/artificial-intelligence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwalsh.io/interests/artificial-intelligence/</guid><description>Generative Models To what degree will our inventions unearth deeper understandings about ourselves? Reinforcement Learning From the Old To the Newer With the Newest</description></item><item><title>Blockchain</title><link>https://wwalsh.io/interests/blockchain/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwalsh.io/interests/blockchain/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fully Automated Data Pipeline Using Free, Cloud-Based Solutions</title><link>https://wwalsh.io/projects/creations/basketball-dataset/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwalsh.io/projects/creations/basketball-dataset/</guid><description>Overview Facilitated other’s sports-analytics data projects by creating the most robust, open-source, NBA-related database. Ensured $0 capital overhead requirements by using free cloud computing and dataset tools. Enabled better testing, deployment, and expansion by containerizing each pipeline segment’s Python scripts.</description></item><item><title>Regularized Linear Regression Models: Implementing Pathwise Coordinate Descent For The Lasso and The Elastic Net In Python Using NumPy</title><link>https://wwalsh.io/publications/implementing-pathwise-coordinate-descent-for-the-lasso-and-the-elastic-net-in-python-using-numpy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwalsh.io/publications/implementing-pathwise-coordinate-descent-for-the-lasso-and-the-elastic-net-in-python-using-numpy/</guid><description>Published in Towards Data Science, this article, part three of a three-part series, explores the concepts of the Lasso for regression, pathwise coordinate descent optimization as a discrete optimization algorithm to find model parameters, and the Elastic Net for regression.</description></item><item><title>Regularized Linear Regression Models: Using Ridge Regression to Overcome Drawbacks of Ordinary Least Squares (OLS)</title><link>https://wwalsh.io/publications/using-ridge-regression-to-overcome-drawbacks-of-ordinary-least-squares/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwalsh.io/publications/using-ridge-regression-to-overcome-drawbacks-of-ordinary-least-squares/</guid><description>Published in Towards Data Science, this article, part two of a three-part series, explores the concepts of model error modeling, model overfitting/underfitting, statistical shrinkage for bias reduction, and Ridge Regression (Tikhonov Regularization)</description></item><item><title>Regularized Linear Regression Models: Basics of Linear Regression Modeling and Ordinary Least Squares (OLS)</title><link>https://wwalsh.io/publications/basics-of-linear-regression-modeling-and-ordinary-least-squares/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwalsh.io/publications/basics-of-linear-regression-modeling-and-ordinary-least-squares/</guid><description>Published in Towards Data Science, this article, part one of a three-part series, explores the concepts of regression, linear modeling, and both derivations and explanations of the ordinary least squares regressor</description></item><item><title> Regularized Linear Regression Deep Dive</title><link>https://wwalsh.io/projects/creations/regularized-regression/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwalsh.io/projects/creations/regularized-regression/</guid><description>Explanations and Python implementations of Ordinary Least Squares regression, Ridge regression, Lasso regression (solved via Coordinate Descent), and Elastic Net regression (also solved via Coordinate Descent) applied to assess wine quality given numerous numerical features. Additional data analysis and visualization in Python is included.</description></item><item><title>Conceptualizing Higher Education Institutions: An Agent-Based Modelling Approach</title><link>https://wwalsh.io/projects/creations/higher-education-simulation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwalsh.io/projects/creations/higher-education-simulation/</guid><description>Overview</description></item><item><title> Machine Learning for NBA Game Attendance Prediction</title><link>https://wwalsh.io/projects/creations/nba-attendance-prediction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwalsh.io/projects/creations/nba-attendance-prediction/</guid><description>The goal of this project was to craft models in order to accurately predict the attendance of a future National Basketball Association (NBA) game. Game data, including attendance, was scraped from stats.nba.com and stadium capacity data collected from numerous online sources. This data was then cleaned, processed, explored through visualizations and statistical tests, and then modeled using many regression techniques including regularized methods, ensemble methods such as Random Forest and Boosting, and neural networks.</description></item><item><title>Mixed Integer Linear Programming for Fair Division Problems</title><link>https://wwalsh.io/projects/creations/mixed-integer-linear-programming-for-fair-division-problems/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 15:00:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwalsh.io/projects/creations/mixed-integer-linear-programming-for-fair-division-problems/</guid><description>The goal of this project is to find optimally fair allocations of divisible and non-divisible goods for a group of people under three different definitions of fairness under envy-freeness with certain assumptions. Mixed-integer linear programming (MILP) formulations are created in AMPL and solved using CPLEX resulting in the generation of datasets consisting of the minimal approximate envy value and solver elapsed time for different combinations of number of people and number of goods.</description></item><item><title>Forcing Visits to use SSL</title><link>https://wwalsh.io/blog/force-ssl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwalsh.io/blog/force-ssl/</guid><description>Intro Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether it&amp;rsquo;s a CakePHP app for a client, your own personal CMS, or any other web based application. If your passing around passwords or other sensitive info you should really implement SSL. SSL provides 2 main perks to your visitors.
First it encrypts all communication that flies across the web. This prevents curious or devious billies from getting your secrets. Secondly it ensures to the user that your server is in fact who it claims, and not a nasty &amp;lsquo;man in the middle&amp;quot; attack.</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning Operations</title><link>https://wwalsh.io/interests/machine-learning-operations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwalsh.io/interests/machine-learning-operations/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Music</title><link>https://wwalsh.io/interests/music/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwalsh.io/interests/music/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Optimization</title><link>https://wwalsh.io/interests/optimization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwalsh.io/interests/optimization/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Physics</title><link>https://wwalsh.io/interests/physics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwalsh.io/interests/physics/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Search Results</title><link>https://wwalsh.io/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wwalsh.io/search/</guid><description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml
[outputs] home = [&amp;#34;HTML&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;JSON&amp;#34;] Searching additional files To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.</description></item></channel></rss>